<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 ratdotnet <auroraaegis87@protonmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # The Khese Müüs
    For millenium, your kind have walked the sun spotted steppes
    of the [bold]Longest Path[/bold] in harmony with nature. Appointed stewards
    of the physical world, tasked with cultivating nature towards a 
    shining resplendence, so that all may rest peacefully when their souls
    pass on.

    Your people, [bold][color=#a4d68c]The Khese Müüs[/color][/bold], are unbreakable. Though their name may
    literally mean "Gentle People", nature has opted to give them all that
    is necessary to make peace through warfare. To any individual Khese, great 
    feats of strength, endurance, and tenacity are but one of many a day's errands
    on the Şalkhîr. Despite this, the Khese exude little in the way of hawkishness 
    or warmongering. Their culture is predicated upon the shamanic worship of the
    natural world, and thus, despite having become a space-faring civilization within
    the last few centuries, your home-world's natural resources are unusually well kept.

    ## First Contact

    The Khese's foray into the stars above was not born from industry or scientific development.
    Rather, it was when they made first contact with representatives from [bold][color=#c12b35]Interdyne Pharmaceuticals[/color][/bold].
    The medical cartel, having recently discovered the system and its
    constituent exoplanets, were ecstatic over the opportunity to research new prospects
    on a super-earth with a largely undamaged biosphere. After preliminary negotiations,
    the most prominent Khese tribes were able to strike an ostensibly benevolent arrangement.
    In secret, however, they remained steadfast and wary. From the very start, the earth beneath them
    emanated a single warning: tread lightly.

    The following decades were rife with conflict, brewing under the surface of the mega-corporations
    imperial project. With the guidance of the world-spirit, the Khese unified under a single cause:
    seizing the means of technological self-sufficiency, and expelling those that would
    damage their fragile paradise. As they integrated further as new players on the galactic stage,
    they entrenched themselves deeper and deeper within the extractive machine encroaching upon their home.
    After a years long insurrection concluding nearly a century of occupation, they boldly declared to the 
    universe a refusal to be pilfered.

    Today, The Khese Müüs have hesitantly set out across the Orion Spur. Many find themselves pursuing education
    and careers in the natural sciences, while others find themselves scouted by asset protection fleets and private
    military contractors. Many still remain on their home-world, content to live as their ancestors did for all time.

</Document>