<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Chief-Engineer <119664036+Chief-Engineer@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 NeKognitoHazard <168395829+NeKognitoHazard@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 TheNeonViking <julian.sean.ison@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Rouge2t7 <81053047+Sarahon@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Tuerk <richardgirgindontstop@gmail.com>
SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Space Law
  Omu Station operates under abbreviated space law. All crew, passengers, and visitors aboard the station are expected to know and follow these laws.

  - [color=#ba292c][bold]Head of Security[/bold][/color] and especially [color=#ba292c][bold]Warden[/bold][/color] should be very familiar with space law.
  - Security players should strive to fully comprehend Space Law.
  - Security players cannot use contraband not assigned to them unless there is a station ending threat, inspect an item to see its legality.
  - [bold]Ignoring or misuse of Space Law may be subject to punishment under incompetence. Do not play security if you do not plan to follow the rules[/bold]

  ## Jurisdiction

  [color=green][bold]Crew:[/bold][/color] Individuals employed by Nanotrasen to maintain and operate the station, including command staff, security forces, and departmental personnel. Individuals without current contracts with Nanotrasen are not crew, and do not enjoy the protections of Space Law unless they are [color=gray]Visitors[/color].

  [color=gray][bold]Visitors[/bold][/color]: Peaceful non-crew personnel with authorized access, such as traders, diplomats, and approved guests who temporarily board the station or its shuttles. Hostile foreigners and entities are not Visitors, and do not enjoy the protections of Space Law.

  The station, shuttles, trade station, arrivals, equipment, materials, and any other entity constructed with materials provided by Nanotrasen or its employees, are the property of Nanotrasen. [color=#1b67a5][bold]Central Command (CentCom)[/bold][/color] is Nanotrasen's organizational structure that has jurisdiction over of the operations of Nanotrasen property and personnel in the Omu Sector.

  Private shuttles—those not owned by Nanotrasen—fall outside this jurisdiction. Visitor shuttles are explicitly private, and unwarranted searches constitute Secure Trespass unless:

  A pursued criminal has boarded the shuttle, regardless of permission.
  There is reasonable suspicion that the shuttle’s occupants intend harm against the station or its crew.
  A crime onboard the shuttle has been visibly witnessed or reported.
  A warrant has been authorized.

  ## Prisoner Rights

  See chapter [textlink="Prisoner's Rights" link="SpaceLawPrisonerRights"].

  ## Searches

  - A personnel search is a seizure of the objects in a person's backpack, hands, coat, belt, pockets, and hat. If any contraband is found during a search the officer may choose to further the search into a detainment or simply confiscate the restricted items. After the search is conducted all legal items are to be returned to the person.

  - A crewmate may legally decline any search conducted without a warrant while the alert level is green. Should be noted that if the alert level is blue or above all personnel searches are legal and no longer require a warrant.

  ## Implantation Procedures

  See chapter [textlink="Implantation Procedures" link="SpaceLawImplantationProcedures"].

  ## Blood testing
  - Blood testing is a procedure that can be used to determine if a person is a [textlink="Changeling" link="Changelings"]. Blood testing may only be forced when there has been confirmation of changelings existence on the station.

  ## Sentencing
  - All sentencing is to be handled by the [color=#ba292c]Warden[/color], if they are not available the [color=#ba292c]HoS[/color] is to take over that duty. If there's no [color=#ba292c]HoS[/color] it falls onto the highest ranking [color=#1b67a5]command[/color] member.

  - Use common sense and humanity when issuing punishments. You should not always seek out the highest punishment you can, you don't have to always give the maximum time or always look to demote someone. Always take in account the severity and only charge for what is needed for someone to learn their lesson.

  - [bold]Accessory, Attempting, And Intention:[/bold] If someone intentionally, knowingly and substantially assists someone in enacting a crime they can be charged with the relevant crimes, such as an engineer giving someone tools, who says they are going to break into an area. Same goes for a clear and solid attempt at a crime, or a person who shows clear intent to act out a crime, such as a syndicate nuclear operative arming a nuke but getting arrested before it goes off, they can still be charged with terrorism. Does not apply to crimes that have an attempted listing already, like attempted murder.

  ## Crime Stacking

  "Crime Stacking", or the procedure for charging someone with multiple crimes simultaneously, is required when someone violates multiple Laws. Crime Stacking involves:
  - Adding the timers for each crime the accused committed. Only the highest relevant crime in a category code (last two digits) should be used.
  - Crimes with the same category code cannot be charged together. e.g: 1-02, 2-02, 3-02 do not stack.
    - Otherwise, crimes can be stacked together; the timers are added together for stacking.

  [italic]For instance, breaking a window to steal something should be charged can be charged with the following[/italic]
    - [italic]1-04 - Petty Theft[/italic]
    - [italic]1-05 - Vandalism[/italic]
    - [italic]1-06 - Trespass[/italic]
        - [italic]See the [textlink="Crime Directory" link="SpaceLawCrimeList"] for category codes.[/italic]

  ## Legal Representation and Trials

  Prisoners have a right to legal representation. Prisoners have a right to a trial for all Capital Punishments unless an exception applies. All other trials are held at the discretion of the Judge. Trial results are final.

  Lawyers offer legal assistance to those accused of crimes, or to aid Security in the just application of the law. In the event there is no legal representation for a prisoner, they are required to act on their behalf. Lawyers have no authority over the operations of Security or sentencing and may be trespassed from Security if their actions become disruptive to the operations of the department. Lawyers handle the following:
  - Advise and assist Security in the sentencing of prisoners.
  - Act as legal consultants to the accused.

  The Judge acts as the highest legal authority on the station. The Judge ensures all trials, civil and criminal, are performed according to the Legal Standard Operating Procedures and that any preparations for a safe and efficient trial are carried out.

  [bolditalic]Should the Judge be unavailable, a neutral, impartial member of the crew should be appointed by the [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color] to serve in that capacity.[/bolditalic] To perform their duties, the Judge may:

  - Remove, enhance, or otherwise change sentences for prisoners as they see fit.
  - Charge individuals with contempt(Failure to Comply) or Perjury during a Trial or during the preparation of a Trial as necessary.
  - Expel individuals who disrupt or disgrace the courtroom.
  - Nominate individuals to serve as Lawyers for the accused or Prosecutors against the accused if necessary.
  - Disqualify or disallow evidence or testimony that is false, misleading, or not germane to the charges alleged.
  - Adjust the Legal Standard Operating Procedures due to exigent circumstances.
  - Any changes require documentation with clear reasoning be sent to Central Command.

  # Execution
  - [bold]All executions are to be confirmed and overseen by the [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color]. Exceptions to this rule exist. A prisoner may request a specific execution method, if reasonable. Otherwise the most humane method is prefered. Refer to Standard Operating Procedure to further understand any guidelines applied to execution.[/bold]

  # Exceptions
  - [bold]If a changeling is discovered they are kill on sight.[/bold]
  - [bold]Any unauthorised magic use should be treated seriously and may be kill on sight[/bold]
  - [bold]Any cases of weapons of mass destruction,extreme terrorism or clear intention to destroy the station are kill on sight[/bold]

  ## SOP guidelines
  - [textlink="Legal" link="Legal SOP"] refer to, for more in-depth guidelines.
  ## Crime Listing
  - [textlink="Crime Listing" link="SpaceLawCrimeList"]
</Document>
