<Document>
  # Plasmamen

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobPlasmaman" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#ffa500]Warning! This species is not recommended for new players due to their tendency to self-ignite![/color]


  ## Mechanics

  [color=#ffa500]They breathe plasma[/color], and [color=#ec3a3a]oxygen is highly toxic to them when inhaled.[/color]
  Being exposed to oxygen [color=#ec3a3a][bold]sets them on fire.[/color][/bold]

  To prevent ignition, they wear sealed suits made up of an envirosuit (in the jumpsuit slot) and a [bold]spaceworthy[/bold] envirosuit helmet.
  Other suits like EVA suits, vacsuits, tacsuits and hardsuits will also seal them from oxygen exposure.

  [color=#1e90ff]
  They don't experience hunger nor thirst.
  They don't have blood and cannot bleed out.
  [/color]

  Due to their skeleton body, they can consume [color=#1e90ff]Milk[/color] to gain a positive moodlet and slowly heal [color=#1e90ff]Brute[/color], [color=#1e90ff]Heat[/color], [color=#1e90ff]Shock[/color], and [color=#1e90ff]Caustic[/color] damage.
  They can also consume [color=#8658fc]Plasma [/color]to gain a bigger positive moodlet and [color=#8658fc] heal every damage type faster[/color], except for Cellular damage.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DrinkCartonMilk" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SheetPlasma1" />
  </Box>

  They infuse their [color=yellow]fists[/color] with plasma dust that combusts when they punch, dealing [color=orange]5 Heat[/color] and [color=red]2.25 Blunt[/color] damage. [bold]However[/bold], each successful punch deals [color=orange]1 Heat[/color] damage to their hands.

  Plasmamen with the traits [color=yellow][bold]Claws[/bold][/color], [color=yellow][bold]Talons[/bold][/color] or [color=yellow][bold]Natural Weapons Removal[/bold][/color] have less unarmed damage but don't take self-damage from unarmed attacks.

  They take [color=#1e90ff]25% less Piercing[/color], [color=#1e90ff]20% less Poison[/color], and [color=#1e90ff]15% less Slash[/color],
  and are [color=#8658fc]immune to Radiation and Cold[/color] damage,
  but take [color=#ffa500]50% more Blunt[/color] and [color=#ffa500]50% more Heat[/color] damage.

  Due to their [color=#8658fc]Cold immunity[/color], they can live in cold environments without the need of a winter coat.

  They have a slightly [color=#ec3a3a]lower density than the average species[/color].
  This results in weaknesses such as but not limited to: being slightly more [color=#ec3a3a]vulnerable to being shoved[/color], [color=#ec3a3a]picked up[/color],
  and having a [color=#ec3a3a]harder time pulling heavy objects[/color].

  ## Equipment
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingUniformEnvirosuit" Caption="envirosuit"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadEnvirohelm" Caption="envirosuit helmet"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoubleEmergencyPlasmaTankFilled" />
  </Box>

  All Plasmamen start with an envirosuit, an envirosuit helmet, and a plasma internals tank.

  Their envirosuits contain a [color=#1e90ff]self-extinguisher[/color] with limited charges, which they can activate when they are on fire
  and wearing their envirosuit helmet. The self-extinguisher needs to recharge between uses.

  <Box HorizontalAlignment="Stretch">
    Cartridge refills of the envirosuit's self-extinguisher can be bought in [bold]Loadouts[/bold], or printed at the medical techfab after research.
    A refill makes a recharging self-extinguisher immediately usable again.
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EnvirosuitExtinguisherRefill" />
  </Box>

  Their envirosuit helmets are [bold]spaceworthy[/bold] and provide welding protection. The helmet's visor can be lit up like a flashlight, using the inserted power cell as a battery.
  They cannot eat nor drink without taking off their envirosuit helmet.

  The plasma internals tank lasts roughly an hour before needing to be replaced or refilled.

  ## Medical Treatment
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StasisBed" />
  </Box>

  Before performing surgery on a Plasmaman, their envirosuit needs to be unequipped first, which is disastrous in an oxygenated environment.

  To get around this, the Plasmaman can be buckled to a [bold]stasis bed[/bold] before removing their envirosuit
  to prevent them from self-igniting throughout the surgical procedure.

  <Box HorizontalAlignment="Stretch">
    Their envirosuit helmets prevents them from eating pills, but their envirosuits allow chemicals to be injected through them.
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Syringe" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

</Document>
