<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Tuerk <richardgirgindontstop@gmail.com>
SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Space Law: Prisoner Rights

  Prisoners who are protected under Space Law have certain rights applied to them to provide humane treatment. The [color=#ba292c]Warden[/color] is to ensure all these conditions are met or face punishment in accordance to Space Law. If the [color=#ba292c]Warden[/color] is not available, the duty falls on the [color=#ba292c]Head of Security[/color], then the [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color].

  Individuals who fall under the Jurisdiction of Space Law have the following rights while in detainment:
  - Prisoners must be granted adequate medical care.
  - Prisoners must be allowed access to basic communications equipment so long as they are not abused.
  - Prisoners must be granted clothing, food, water, shelter and safety. If the brig is no longer safe, temporary confinement must be established in another location.
  - Prisoners must be given access to legal counsel. If no legal counsel is present, a member of the crew must be appointed to serve in that capacity for the prisoner.
  - Prisoners must be given a trial for all Capital Punishments.
  - Prisoners must be given their shift mandated PDA after confinement has finished, unless there is proof of PDA tampering. In case of tampering, the PDA is to be secured and replaced with a new unit.
  - Prisoners must be granted freedom of movement and should not be restrained with handcuffs or other devices after incarceration unless there is an undue risk to life and limb.
  - Prisoners should not be confined to a solitary cell unless they pose a risk to others or the security of their confinement

  Prisoners [bold]cannot[/bold] be executed without a trial unless:
  - They repeatedly damage their cell to the point that safe confinement is unreasonable.
  - They repeatedly attack and cause serious injury to other prisoners making the safe confinement of other prisoners unreasonable.
  - They escape confinement while charged with or awaiting trial for a Capital Punishment.
  - They undergo a blood test that proves they are not a member of the Crew or a Visitor.
  - They have illegal implants that are unable to be removed.
</Document>
