<Document>
  # Nanotrasen Career Trainer (NCT) SOP
  This document outlines the procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#a91169][bold]Nanotrasen Career Trainer[/bold][/color] aboard the station.

  <ColorBox>
    <Box HorizontalAlignment="Center" Margin="10">
      The [color=#a91169][bold]Nanotrasen Career Trainer[/bold][/color] must never serve as Captain or Head of Staff.
    </Box>
  </ColorBox>

  ## Overview
  As a Nanotrasen Career Trainer, you are responsible for training and evaluating the station's crew. Your primary duty is to ensure that all employees are performing to the best of their abilities while adhering to company protocols and standards.

  ## Duties
  - Train new employees on their assigned roles and responsibilities.
  - Evaluate crew performance and provide constructive feedback.
  - Assist with onboarding and orientation of new hires.
  - Maintain accurate training records and certifications.

  ## Regulations and Limitations

  1. The Nanotrasen Career Trainer is solely responsible for the training and evaluation of the station's crew.
  They [bold]must not[/bold] interfere with command decisions or the standard operations of the station beyond training or evaluation purposes.
    <Box>- The Nanotrasen Career Trainer should remain neutral and avoid any attempts to meddle in station conflicts or operational matters.</Box>

  2. The Nanotrasen Career Trainer must prioritize their own safety above all else, as they are a [bold]Central Command Asset[/bold].
    <Box>- If the Nanotrasen Career Trainer is placed in danger, they are to use their pre-equipped Bluespace Lifeline to ensure their safety.</Box>

  3. The Nanotrasen Career Trainer is not permitted to interfere with any demotions or arrests. Doing so constitutes a violation of Central Command directives and Space Law.
    <Box>- An exception is permitted only when such involvement is strictly necessary for training, evaluation, or onboarding purposes.</Box>

  4. The Nanotrasen Career Trainer is permitted to assist station departments in any capacity they deem appropriate, provided such assistance does not interfere with their primary training and evaluation duties.
    <Box>- If a department requests assistance from the Nanotrasen Career Trainer, they may provide support at their discretion.</Box>
</Document>
