<Document>
  # Omustation Server Rules
  Welcome to Omustation!
  While most of our rules are pretty self-explenatory and common sense, it's still good to give them a read. Just in case. They aren't too long!

  We are an MRP server, so in here roleplay is king, and [textlink="admins can disregard these rules" link="RuleAdmins"] should it prove beneficial for the experience of the shift. Admins are also allowed to intervene in rounds when it is in the best interest of the player base.

  [color=yellow]This is a 16+ server[/color], and you will be banned if you are under age.

  Remember that the ways these rules are enforced are ultimately up to the admins enforcing them. If you think an adnmin is abusing their power or enforcing the rules incorrectly, you can always make a ticket on discord

  ## Core Rules

  - [textlink="1. Don't be a dick" link="RuleDontBeADick"]
  - [textlink="2. Don't metagame" link="RuleMetagame"]
  - [textlink="3. Keep IC and OOC seperate" link="RuleICKOCK"]
  - [textlink="4. Don't Self-antag" link="RuleSelfantag"]
  - [textlink="5. No Bigotry" link="RuleBigotry"]
  - [textlink="6. No Explicit/Shock Content" link="RuleNSFW"]
  - [textlink="7. Speak in english only" link="RuleEnglish"]
  - [textlink="8. No Hacking, Exploiting, or using macros." link="RuleHacker"]
  - [textlink="9. Don't be excessively incompetent" link="RuleSkillIssue"]


  ## Roleplay Rules

  - [textlink="1. Put effort into your rp." link="RuleEffort"]
  - [textlink="2. Don't make a character that ruins the fun for others." link="RuleBadRP"]
  - [textlink="3. Don't over-esalate." link="RuleEscelate"]


  ## Silicon rules

  Silicons, while needing to follow the server rules like anyone else, also get their own laws that they need to follow.


  Following your laws is not selfantagging, and if your laws say you need to kill someone, then you gotta kill them.


  [bolditalic]HOWEVER[/bolditalic], if someone is ordering you to do something that is against server rules, such as say a slur, then you should ahelp it immediately and act like the order was never said.
  Silicons are players too, so [textlink="Rule 1. Don't be a dick" link="RuleDontBeADick"] still applies to them, along with orders you are given.


  If you have multiple conflicting laws, then the law which is higher up on your laws list takes priority.
  This means that a law like "Law 0: kill everyone" would override "Law 1: you cannot let a crewmember come to harm"

  ## Ahelping and you

  [head=3] ALWAYS AHELP [/head] if you think someone is breaking these rules or is otherwise being a problem.
  If admins don't respond, the issue may have been resolved without a responce.


  Even if there aren't any admins on, we can see past ahelps from previous rounds, and can deal with problem players when we get on!


  Also, [textlink="don't be a dick" link="RuleDontBeADick"] in ahelps. If you're ahelping, you're probably already mad about something, so be extra careful to not get into a pointless fight.
  When you're angry and yelling, people generally don't like to listen, and admins are people too!
</Document>

