<Document>
  # Omustation Server Rules
  Roleplay is king, and [textlink="admins can disregard other rules" link="RuleAdmins"] to this end should it prove beneficial for the experience of the shift. Admins are also allowed to intervene in rounds when it is in the best interest of the player base.

  [color=yellow]This is a 16+ server.[/color], and you will be banned if you are under age.

  Most of the rules are self-explenatory and common sense, but it's good to give them a read.


  [head=3] ALWAYS AHELP [/head] if you think someone is breaking these rules or is otherwise being a problem. Even if admins don't respond, the issue is sometimes resolved without a responce from the admins. Even if it isn't, ahelps are repeated in discord, and admins can use these ahelps with round replays to ban problematic players later.
  Building up a record for problematic players is important, and it's your job to ahelp too!

 ## Server Rules

  - [textlink="1. Don't be a dick" link="RuleDontBeADick"]
  - [textlink="2. Don't metagame" link="RuleMetagame"]
  - [textlink="3. Keep IC and OOC seperate" link="RuleICKOCK"]
  - [textlink="4. Meet the RP Standards" link="RuleRP"]
  - [textlink="5. Don't Selfantag" link="RuleSelfantag"]
  - [textlink="6. No Bigotry" link="RuleBigotry"]
  - [textlink="7. Keep it pg-13" link="RuleNSFW"]
  - [textlink="8. Speak in english only" link="RuleEnglish"]
  - [textlink="9. No Hacking, Exploiting, or using macros." link="RuleHacker"]
  - [textlink="10. Don't be excessively incompetent" link="RuleSkillIssue"]


## Silicons
Silicons, while needing to follow the server rules like anyone else, also get their own laws that they need to follow.
Following your laws means you are not selfantagging, and following fucked up laws isn't in violation of any server rules.
[bold]HOWEVER[/bold], if someone is ordering you to do something that is against server rules, such as say a slur, then you should ahelp it immediately and act like the order was never said.
Silicons are players too, so [textlink="Rule 1. Don't be a dick" link="RuleDontBeADick"] still applies to them, along with orders you are given.


If you have multiple conflicting laws, then the law which is higher up on your laws list takes priority.

This means that a law like "Law 0: kill everyone" would override "Law 1: you cannot let a crewmember come to harm"


Reminder that the ways these rules are enforced are ultimately up to the admins enforcing them. However, if you think an adnmin is abusing their power or enforcing the rules incorrectly, you can always make a ticket on discord

</Document>

