<Document>
# Chaplain
There's something about the vast infinity of space that turns men to prayer... Especially if they get thrown into it without a space suit.


As a chaplain, you would ideally proselytize whatever crazy religion you've made up for that round over your headset. However, besides your office, the hellish crematorium next to your office, and the rarely used morgue, you have no access.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Bible"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Nullrod"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ArmamentsBeacon"/>
  </Box>

## Religions:
You are free to propagate any present day religions you know of, or even invent one of your own! Just make sure it doesn't go against NanoTrasen and its values, or you may well end up in the brig.

If you don't already have one, build an altar and find an offering to place on-top:

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarBananium"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarChaos"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarDruid"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarClock"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarFangs"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarHeaven"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarConvertMaint"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarNanotrasen"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarSpaceChristian"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarTechnology"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarToolbox"/>
  </Box>

These altars can be constructed by placing the following offerings atop your base convert altar:

- Bananium Altar: 1 x Bananium
- Chaos Altar: 1 x Plasma
- Druid Altar: 1 x Wooden Plank
- Fanged Altar: 1 x Raw Meat
- Heaven Altar: 1 x Templar Helmet
- Maints Altar: 1 x Budget Insulated Gloves
- Nanotrasen Altar: 1 x Plasteel
- Space-Christian Altar: 1 x Nun Hood
- Technology Altar: 1 x Capacitor
- Toolbox Altar: 1 x Toolbox
- Clockwork Altar: 1 x Small Power Cell

## Holy Artefacts

### Armaments Beacon
Allows you to choose a set of armor. All armors have identical stats.

### Null Rod
  The Null Rod, while mighty, is capable of far more than just bludgeoning. It can be changed into many [bold]special variants[/bold] depending on what altar you place it on.
  [Color=blue][bold]All variants of the Null Rod, unless stated otherwise, provide immunity to the effects of magic while held.[/bold][/color]

  ### Null Rod [Default]
  The obsidian rod will be your defense against the forces of evil.
  It's basic, but reliable. Sometimes all you need is a good 'ole whack on the head.

  Does good damage (10 blunt and 10 holy) at average speed

  ### Atheist's Fedora [Nanotrasen Altar]
  Not so much a fan of the divine? Prefer to worship our corporate overlords? Use space-reddit regularly?
  Boy do we have the weapon for you.

  This fedora can both be worn as a stylish fashion statement, and tossed like a knife!
  And to add insult to injury, [bold]it returns after being thrown![/bold]

  Deals low melee damage (5 slash and 10 holy) with average throwing damage (10 slash and 10 holy) with average attack speed.

  ### God Hand [Chaos Altar]
  A searing, blazing, divine gift from the Gods themselves.
  You won't ever drop this one, it's your new hand!

  Not only can you punch people directly in the throat with this, it'll [italic]also[/italic] [color=red]light them on fire and force them into your grasp.[/color]
  Additionally, you may use it to pry open certain objects!

  Deals good damage (10 Heat, 4 slash and 10 holy) at average speed with the added utility of instant hard grab.

  ### Holy Claymore [Heaven Altar]
  A righteous blade fit for a righteous crusader.
  Does the phrase "[color=yellow]DEUS VULT![/color]" ignite something within you?
  You may enjoy this weapon then!

  This weapon functions as a normal sword, effective at slashing and cleaving the unclean from your station.
  As a bonus, right-clicking with this weapon while wielding it will fire a [color=yellow]bolt of holy energy from the blade.[/color]

  Hitting an enemy who is marked with one of these bolts will both deal more damage [color=green]and heal you for twenty brute, and ten airloss.[/color]

  Deals good damage (13 slash and 10 holy) with the additional utility as above. It's melee speed is average with a 0.5 shots per second ranged bolt.

  ### Monk's Staff [Nature Altar]
  A long, polished, wooden rod. Typically used to beat the literal and metaphorical Devil out of someone.

  While dealing a relatively low amount of damage, [color=blue]the Monk's Staff can be swung incredibly fast.[/color]
  The fast attack speed combined with its holy damage make it incredibly effective at crippling any unholy entities quickly.

  Deals low damage (2.5 blunt and 6 holy) with additional stamina damage (10) at a fast attack speed.

  ### His Holy Chainsaw [Toolbox Altar]
  Sometimes all you need to do is [color=red]rip... and tear.[/color]
  This [italic]does[/italic] replace your hand with a chainsaw so... just be aware of that.

  This weapon has both an incredibly fast attack speed, even faster than the Monk's Staff, along with the ability to inflict especially nasty wounds.
  A chainsaw, as one would imagine, is very proficient in ripping things limb from limb.

  Additionally, it's quite good at tearing down walls and doors.

  Needs weilding, but deals low damage (2 blunt, 3 slash and 6 holy. With 20 structural to tear into places) at a fast attack speed.

  ### Rosary [Space Christian Altar]
  In comparison to the other Nullrod variants, the Rosary hits with the force of a cardboard tube.
  Where it's [color=yellow]true strength[/color] comes in is it's ability to heal nearby creatures with it's holy aura.

  When praying to the Rosary, all other creatures will be healed by [color=green] 22.5 Brute, 7.5 Heat, 7.5 Cold, 7.5 Shock per tick,[/color][color=yellow] and deal holy damage to any demons nearby.[/color]
  While this may sound like a lot, when spread across the entire body it is a far more reasonable number.

  If you hold the Rosary in two hands, you may walk slightly faster while doing so.
  Also, it can be worn in the belt slot!

  Strangely enough, does little damage, (3 blunt and 10 holy), its real utility is the AoE heal which will deal holy damage to the unholy.

  ### Casul & Jackal [Technology Altar]
  Not a fan of getting your hands dirty?
  This pair of legally-distinct, copyright free handguns are perfect for you!

  Both pistols come in a specially made holster designed specifically to hold them.
  Due to the holy awesomeness of them, you can only fire when holding both of them at once, with one in each hand.

  Each pistol does low damage, but are both fired together (5 peircing and 4 holy)

  Out of ammo? No worries! Just pray to whatever God you believe in for a new clip of ammo and get back to shooting demons!

  ### Grey Emperor's Glove [Maintenance Altar]
  Holding this weapon fills your head with the word "Self-antag"... What does that mean?
  You can't drop this one either!

  You may use this weapon to strike foes and send them flying through the air with the power of the Grey-Tide.
  As a neat function, you may also use this weapon as almost any type of tool, and it's completely insulated!

  Deals nice damage (14 holy and 9 blunt) with average attack speed.

  ### Arythmic Knife [Fanged Altar]
  They say fear is the true mind killer, but you can just stab them. Let that flow through em, eh?
  Randomly speeds you up and slows you down, between 0.6x move speed and 2.0x move speed, thats fast!

  Average attack speed and lowish damage (9 slash and 10 holy).

  ### Honkmother's maw [Bananium Altar]
  Oh great, another clown, just what we need.
  Slips targets on hit, very potent! Comes with a cooldown so you can't slip-lock someone.

  Average attack speed and lowish damage (10 blunt and 12 holy)

### Enchanting

You can use your Bible and any Altar of your choosing to [textlink="enchant items." link="Enchanting"]

### Spirit Candles
You can craft a spirit candle by putting a candle on a skull. Spirit Candles are useful against evil spirits like Wraith.

When they are ignited, they create a 12x12 tile area that reveals evil spirits. It also has a special function when you use it in-hand.
By using it [bold]when an evil spirit is within(!!) your 12x12 area[/bold], it will make them corporeal.

It has 2 charges per spirit candle, and [bold]it only consumes a charge when you reveal the evil spirit[/bold].

It drops the skull once the candle has melted, so you can craft another one.

## Duties

- Church Services: Give sermons and sing hymns.
- Proselytizing: Most crew members are godless heathens, show them god's love.
- Burial Services: Security or Medical may require someone, or something... to be cremated, familiarise yourself with your Chapel so you can make things quick!
- [bold] Metaphysical Investigation: Most crew aren't aware of the threats posed by the unholy, be on the look out for anything suspicious. [/bold]

### Metaphysical Threats
As Chaplain you are the first line of defence against metaphysical threats, [bold] ready your Null Rod - the time is now. [/bold]

[color=red][bold] Use of excessive force against targets which you cannot confirm are metaphysical threats may land you in trouble with the law, use caution and investigate carefully. [/bold][/color]

</Document>
