<Document>
  # Command Training Manual

  Welcome to your new job, command member.

  We at Nanotrasen praise your dedication to safety and willingness to do anything for the wellbeing and profits of the corporation.
  Below, you will find training material regarding the confidential information you were informed of prior.

  The following material is available for your reference, training, and use.
  The information is designed to assist Command members in their professional development.
  Please use the material to expand your understanding, enhance your professional knowledge, to further your career, and possibly receive a stamp of approval from Central Command.

  Please also remember that all of this material is [bold]confidential,[/bold] as per the NDA you signed on employment.
  Failure to comply with the terms of your employment will be met with swift legal action.

  ## Section I. Confidentiality

  All the information in this document is for your eyes only. You, and your fellow command members, should be well read on this information. Remember a happy station is a station with no holes in it.

  You are to inform security and other heads of any suspicious or dangerous situations. As command members you are to ensure station works as efficently as possible with as little slowdown or inconveniences as you can manage. 

  ## Section II. Common knowledge Threats 

  Below you will find a list of threats and recommended action to dealing with them.

  [color=red]This is recommended action, not explicit operating procedure.[/color]
  We at Nanotrasen understand that shifts may deviate from the expected results, so no action will be taken against you or your fellow crew mates for mistakes.

  - [bold]Petty thieves[/bold]

  Typical Alert level: Blue
   
  Petty thievery is common but generally just a nuisance, but we don't need to tell you that. You can use your common sense to put 2 and 2 together.
  These thieves may have contraband that your security team is not made aware of. Inform security if you are missing anything critically important or unique to you, your job or your department.

  - [bold]Undercover Syndicate Agents[/bold]

  Typical Alert level: Blue - Red
   
  Nanotrasen property and people are a consistent target for the Syndicate, the syndicate is comprised of many smaller companies that have decided they prefer revenge over profit. We are aware of a handful of possible companies, dogwhistles and problem slogans. Below is a list of things to look out for.

   Problem companies:
   - Cybersun
   - Interdyne
   - Donk Co
   - Waffle Co

   Etc
   
   Problem Quotes:
   
   -"Glory to the syndicate"
   -"I need to kill the Captain"
   -"Viva" (Discretion advised, some individuals may just be Spanish/Italian/Portuguese or some other flavor of earthlike)
   -"I'm going to loose"

   On top of many other things to be considered. Please be sure to inform security about any of this information.

  - [bold]Revolutionaries[/bold]

  Typical Alert level: Blue - Red
   
  Nanotrasen crewmembers may become upset with the working conditions and/or are French. Consider dealing with this as efficently as possible, either through pay deductions or 'accidentally' having security beat them with a battery depleted baton.
  However, if the crew remains dissatisfied with the working conditions, it is possible that their loyalty to Nanotrasen has been tampered with, also known as mindcontrol. Something Nanotrasen would never do.
  Instruct the security team to mindshield as many crewmates as possible, arresting and mindshielding any crew members spearheading the cause.
  In the event of a particularly disruptive head revolutionary, execution should be seriously considered. Mindshields will fail on such individuals.

  - [bold]Blob Xenofauna[/bold]
   
  Typical Alert level: Blue

  Central Command's sensors can detect any dangerous xenofauna above a certain size, and will send an automatic announcement. Neutralize the threat as soon as possible, under any circumstance.

  - [bold]Changelings[/bold]

  Typical Alert level: Red

  Some crew mates may not be crew mates at all; a hostile predatory life form, colloquially known as changelings, may have taken a similar form as them.
  These creatures are to be dealt with discreetly and quickly, as they require the death of crew in order to survive.
  These life forms have rumoured to be extinct, however if they are still around and on station, the paramedic may feel overworked and come into contact with a very obviously hollowed body.

  - [bold]Dragons and Carp[/bold]

  Typical Alert level: Red

  Dragons are incredibly territorial and hostile xenofauna, and they should be dealt with as quickly as possible.
  Nanotrasen encourages the security team to try and keep crew from panicking.

  - [bold]Ninjas[/bold]
  Typical Alert level: Red

  Some people may attempt to infiltrate the station with the goal of stealing Nanotrasen secrets and research. These are likely part of the Spider Clan — colloquially known as 'Ninja's', and they should be dealt with as soon as possible. 
  They are also known to blow themselves up if captured or placed into critical condition. They are particularly prone to being found in science departments. Let the security team handle this threat.

  - [bold]Heretics[/bold]

  Typical Alert level: Red

  Some individual crewmates may find 'alternative Gods' to follow. There's even rumours that they have been able to harness the power from these 'alternative Gods'
  The Head of Security should prioritise handling these people as soon as possible, before they give the crew ideas.

  - [bold]Cults[/bold]

  Typical Alert level: Red

  This is what happens when security does not handle cultists fast enough.
  The Chaplain has been well informed about cultists, as this is their area of expertise. 
  The Head of Security should encourage and protect the Chaplain if there's talks of cult activity on the station.
 
  - [bold]Zombies[/bold]

  Typical Alert level: Violet

  In the event of a zombie infection, the Chief Medical Officer and their associated medical team should be made the highest priority on the station.
  Due to the nature of zombie infections, encourage crew to stay clear of hallways and out of sight, being bit is an immediate death sentence. The station alert level should be set to Violet and go into an emergency state.

  ## Section III. Rare or rumoured threats

  - [bold]Revenants[/bold]

  Typical Alert level: Blue

  Some former crew mates may find it hard to move on after an untimely death caused by their own negligence.
  Nanotrasen recommends enlisting the Chaplain as an exorcist, without letting the living crew know about any prior deaths on the station.
   
  - [bold]Nuclear Agents[/bold]

  Typical Alert level: Red

  It is rumoured that the syndicate have cobbled together an elite team that would be able to aggressively infiltrate and use our own nuclear device against us. While we believe this is propaganda, we are prepared for the reality.
  If any individuals that look like nuclear operatives appear on station. Arm everyone, because this will be a fight you MUST win, otherwise we are losing a lot of productivity and scientific research.

  ## Section IV. PANIC - PANIC - PANIC

  - [bold]Wizards[/bold]
   
  Typical Alert level: Red
   
  We hate them. Magic isn't real, be sure they are informed of this.

</Document>
